onegreenplanet.org 2019-04-02

# Privacy Policy - One Green PlanetOne Green Planet

The privacy of our visitors is very important to us. This privacy policy describes what types of information we receive and collect when you use and visit OneGreenPlanet.org and how we safeguard your information.

**Information Collected**

_Personally Identifiable Information_

Personally-identifiable information is information that identifies or can be used to identify a user as a specific individual, such as a name, email address, mailing address and phone number.

We collect personally-identifiable information about you only if you voluntarily provide that information when you fill out a form, submit an article or recipe, enter a contest or giveaway, submit a product review or post a comment on this site.

_Non-Personally Identifiable Information_

Non-personally identifiable information includes demographic information (such as age, gender, city or state) and a user’s click stream information.  We collect non-personally identifiable information in the following instances:

_Log Files_

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files.  The information in the log files include  non-personally identifiable information that your browser automatically sends whenever you visit OneGreenPlanet.org, including your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP, browser type, browser language, date and time of the request.

_Cookies and web beacons_

Cookies are small text files that are stored within a browser. They are accessed and recorded by the web site visited and by the companies that show ads on that site to enable them to recognize the same browser or user. Web beacons are small electronic files that allow a web site to count users who have visited that page or to access certain cookies.  The OneGreenPlanet.org site uses web beacons in order to analyze the performance and usefulness of our site.

We may use services provided by third parties like [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics), [Quantcast](https://www.quantcast.com/) and [Chartbeat](https://chartbeat.com/) to track usage on our site. In addition, we have implemented social sharing buttons on OneGreenPlanet.org, so you can easily “Like” or share our content via, [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/), [Pinterest](http://www.pinterest.com/), [Linkedin](https://www.linkedin.com/), [StumbleUpon](http://www.stumbleupon.com/), [Google+](https://plus.google.com/), [Reddit](http://www.reddit.com/), etc. These third parties have their own privacy policies, which you can view through their respective websites. Some of these third parties store cookies in your browser.

We also use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

We serve [Ad Council PSAs](http://www.adcouncil.org/) that involves the uses of Google’s DART cookies to serve ads on OneGreenPlanet.org. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>.

One Green Planet has no access to or control over these cookies used by third parties. The OneGreenPlanet.org privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers, services or web sites.

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to log in to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

**Information use**

_Personally-Identifiable Information_

We use the personally-identifiable information you provide through the OneGreenPlanet.org site to respond to your inquiries and requests and to keep accurate records concerning the services you are requesting through OneGreenPlanet.org, including but not limited to improving our website based on the information and feedback we receive from you, administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature, send you information, respond to inquiries and/or other requests or questions, etc.

_Non-Personally Identifiable Information_

We uses non-personally identifiable information in aggregated form to help us measure the OneGreenPlanet.org site’s performance and effectiveness and to improve its usefulness.

**Information Disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to your personally identifiable information to third parties without your consent. This does not include selected partners, vendors, agents or other third parties, who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, provide products or services you have requested, or when we have your permission.  We may share information about you if One Green Planet LLC is acquired or merged with another company. We may also share information in the event that we are asked to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, or as otherwise permitted by law.

**Security**

We maintain safeguards to help protect the security, integrity and privacy of the personally-identifiable information within our control. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to protect your information, please be advised that we assume no responsibility or liability for disclosure of your information due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third-party access or other causes beyond our control.

**Third party links**

We do not control the data collection policies of any website linked to the OneGreenPlanet.org site. If you click on a link or an advertisement, the privacy policy of the website that you link to will govern the collection and use of your information by that website’s operators.  These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites with respect to their use of your information or otherwise. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Collection of Information from Minors**

The OneGreenPlanet.org site is directed to, and intended for use by, adults only. We do not knowingly collect personally-identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personally identifiable information from a user under the age of thirteen, we will delete such information from our records.

**Acceptance of Privacy Policy**

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through OneGreenPlanet.org and not to information collected offline or via other means. When you use the OneGreenPlanet.org site, you are accepting the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, and we will have the right to use your information as described in this Privacy Policy.  If you do not agree to have your information used in any of the ways described in this Privacy Policy, you must discontinue use of the OneGreenPlanet.org Site. We may update this privacy policy at any time to reflect changes in our practices and service offerings. If we modify this privacy policy, we will update the “Effective Date.” Your continued use of the OneGreenPlanet.or Site after a change in the Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of those changes.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#6c18090d012c0302090b1e0909021c000d02091842031e0b)

_Effective Date: February 15, 2011_

___Last Updated: November 13, 2013_
